=His Chosen Favor=
=مفضلته المختارة=
(The Most Familiar Stranger)
(الغريب الأكثر ألفة)
=Episode 20=
=الحلقة 20=
You're terrified.
أنت مرعوب.
(What's going on?)
(ماذا يحدث هنا؟)
Drag him out and dismember him.
اسحبه للخارج وقطّعه إرباً.
(Never mind. Save Fu An first.)
(لا يهم. أنقذ فو آن أولاً.)
Yes.
نعم.
Wait!
انتظر!
He tried to assassinate me.
لقد حاول اغتيالي.
Killing him like this
قتله بهذه الطريقة
would be far too merciful.
سيكون ذلك رحمة مفرطة.
What do you suggest?
ماذا تقترح؟
Throw him into the prison.
ألقوا به في السجن.
I'll make him suffer.
سأجعله يعاني.
Good! Truly worthy of being my empress.
جيد! إنها حقاً جديرة بأن تكون إمبراطورتي.
Lu Zhen'er! Xiao Yicheng!
لو زينير! شياو ييتشنغ!
You adulterous ones will die horribly!
أيها الزناة، ستموتون ميتة شنيعة!
Drag him away now!
اسحبه بعيداً الآن!
- Yes!
- نعم!
Move!
يتحرك!
You're acting so strangely today.
تتصرفين بشكل غريب للغاية اليوم.
What?
ماذا؟
Strange?
غريب؟
Not at all.
مُطْلَقاً.
Let's sleep.
هيا ننام.
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك،
I was frightened just now
لقد شعرت بالخوف للتو
and feel a bit unwell now.
وأشعر ببعض التوعك الآن.
- Summon the imperial physician. - No.
- استدعِ الطبيب الإمبراطوري. - لا.
I need to sleep alone.
أحتاج إلى النوم بمفردي.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Rest well today.
استرح جيداً اليوم.
I will visit you tomorrow.
سأزورك غداً.
(Everything has changed.)
(لقد تغير كل شيء.)
(Where is Xiao Wenjing?)
(أين شياو وينجينغ؟)
(I must ask Fu An about it.)
(يجب أن أسأل فو آن عن ذلك.)
Fu An.
فو آن.
Are you here to kill me?
هل أنت هنا لقتلي؟
Fu An!
فو آن!
Why did I wake up to find
لماذا استيقظت لأجد
Xiao Yicheng has become the Emperor?
هل أصبح شياو ييتشنغ الإمبراطور؟
Where is Xiao Wenjing?
أين شياو وينجينغ؟
Where is the real Xiao Wenjing?
أين شياو وينجينغ الحقيقية؟
Kill me if you must.
اقتلني إن كان لا بد من ذلك.
Stop pretending.
توقف عن التظاهر.
I'm not pretending!
أنا لا أتظاهر!
What about Yindan?
وماذا عن يندان؟
Does Yindan exist in this world?
هل يوجد يندان في هذا العالم؟
What year is it now?
كم سنة الآن؟
Which world am I in?
في أي عالم أنا؟
Yindan died three months ago.
توفي يندان قبل ثلاثة أشهر.
What are you talking about?
عن ماذا تتحدث؟
Three months?
ثلاثة أشهر؟
Did she die on the night of her birthday?
هل توفيت في ليلة عيد ميلادها؟
Yes.
نعم.
That day, I brought a cake.
في ذلك اليوم، أحضرت كعكة.
You were setting off fireworks outside.
كنتَ تُطلق الألعاب النارية في الخارج.
Xiao Wenjing and I pushed the door open
دفعت أنا وشياو وينجينغ الباب لفتحه
and saw my sister...
ورأيت أختي...
But that happened months ago!
لكن ذلك حدث قبل أشهر!
So after three months,
وبعد ثلاثة أشهر،
I'm still in this world?
هل ما زلتُ في هذا العالم؟
Xiao Wenjing and I were just at the seaside.
كنت أنا وشياو وينجينغ على شاطئ البحر.
Why did I suddenly skip to three months later?
لماذا انتقلت فجأة إلى ثلاثة أشهر لاحقة؟
What actually happened?
ما الذي حدث بالفعل؟
Tell me!
أخبرني!
You and Xiao Yicheng conspired,
تآمرت أنت وشياو ييتشنغ.
plunged the court into chaos, and imprisoned His Majesty!
أغرق البلاط في الفوضى، وسجن جلالته!
After Xiao Yicheng ascended the throne, he made you Empress.
بعد أن اعتلى شياو ييتشنغ العرش، جعلكِ إمبراطورة.
You killed all the maids and eunuchs
لقد قتلت جميع الخادمات والخصيان
in the Zhaohua Hall and the Zichen Hall.
في قاعة تشاوهوا وقاعة زيتشن.
Besides,
بجانب،
you both are obsessed with elixir of immortality.
كلاكما مهووس بإكسير الخلود.
Hearing that blood of boys and girls could be used in the potion,
بعد سماع أن دماء الأولاد والبنات يمكن استخدامها في تحضير الجرعة،
you even...
أنت حتى...
I did all this?
هل فعلت كل هذا؟
Yes.
نعم.
You controlled His Majesty's mind,
لقد سيطرت على عقل جلالته،
so he lost his true self.
وهكذا فقد ذاته الحقيقية.
Which one?
أيها؟
My heart holds only one.
قلبي لا يحمل إلا واحداً.
Xiao Wenjing is still alive?
هل ما زال شياو وينجينغ على قيد الحياة؟
I haven't seen
لم أرَ
His Majesty for a very long time.
جلالته لفترة طويلة جداً.
(All living beings have their destined fate.)
(لكل الكائنات الحية مصيرها المقدر.)
(I must find Xiao Yicheng)
يجب أن أجد شياو ييتشنغ.
(to learn where Xiao Wenjing is.)
(لمعرفة مكان وجود شياو وينجينغ.)
Zhen'er, what brings you here?
زين إير، ما الذي أتى بك إلى هنا؟
I want to see Xiao Wenjing.
أريد أن أرى شياو وينجينغ.
Why are you suddenly concerned about him?
لماذا تشعرين بالقلق عليه فجأة؟
I need to speak with him. Where is he?
أحتاج للتحدث معه. أين هو؟
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
Where is he?
أين هو؟
You've been very strange these days.
لقد كنت غريب الأطوار للغاية هذه الأيام.
Let me see Xiao Wenjing.
دعني أرى شياو وينجينغ.
You may speak to me properly.
يمكنك التحدث معي بشكل لائق.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Let me see Xiao Wenjing!
اسمحوا لي أن أرى شياو وينجينغ!
(Thank goodness,)
(شكرا لله،)
(you're alive.)
(أنت على قيد الحياة.)
♪Having endured sorrow and joy♪
♪بعد أن تحملنا الحزن والفرح♪
♪Wandering the streets, the story unfinished♪
♪أتجول في الشوارع، والقصة لم تكتمل♪
♪Turning around, I lost you♪
♪استدرت، ففقدتك♪
♪Separated by the dust of the past♪
♪يفصل بينهما غبار الماضي♪
♪Our reunion veiled by moonlight♪
♪لقاءنا محجوب بضوء القمر♪
♪Grant me indifference or tenderness♪
♪امنحني اللامبالاة أو الحنان♪
♪Crowds push past, brushing shoulders♪
♪تتدافع الحشود، وتتلامس الأكتاف♪
Xiao Wenjing,
شياو ون جينغ
this is my Consort Lu!
هذه هي قرينتي لو!
Let go!
اتركه!
She wants to kill you.
إنها تريد قتلك.
It's all a misunderstanding.
الأمر كله سوء فهم.
I'm Lu Zhen'er, Xiao Wenjing.
أنا لو زينير، شياو وينجينغ.
Let go.
اتركه.
You want to kill me?
أتريد قتلي؟
Anyone who threatens my father must die.
كل من يهدد والدي يجب أن يموت.
What did you call him?
ماذا كنت تناديه؟
Zhen'er,
زينير،
you've forgotten me again.
لقد نسيتني مرة أخرى.
I'm the Emperor.
أنا الإمبراطور.
You are the Emperor?
أنت الإمبراطور؟
Yes.
نعم.
You're the late emperor?
أنت الإمبراطور الراحل؟
Why?
لماذا؟
This is impossible.
هذا مستحيل.
Impossible.
مستحيل.
Why?
لماذا؟
Why are there
لماذا يوجد
so many weird things in this palace?
هل يوجد الكثير من الأشياء الغريبة في هذا القصر؟
I'll have them cleared out tomorrow.
سأقوم بإخلائها غداً.
(Why isn't the world reset?)
(لماذا لا تتم إعادة ضبط العالم؟)
(Why is Yindan dead?)
(لماذا مات يندان؟)
(Why doesn't Xiao Wenjing remember me?)
(لماذا لا تتذكرني شياو وينجينغ؟)
(Why is he standing before me,)
(لماذا يقف أمامي؟)
(yet so distant?)
(ومع ذلك فهي بعيدة جدًا؟)
(Why?)
(لماذا؟)
(No.)
(لا.)
(I must get to the bottom of this.)
(يجب أن أصل إلى حقيقة هذا الأمر.)
Xiao Wenjing,
شياو ون جينغ
do you not remember me?
ألا تتذكرني؟
I'm Lu Zhen'er!
أنا لو زينير!
Let go!
اتركه!
Xiao Wenjing,
شياو ون جينغ
look at me closely.
انظر إليّ جيداً.
I'm Lu Zhen'er!
أنا لو زينير!
You recognize me, right?
أنت تعرفني، أليس كذلك؟
You are my father's wife,
أنتِ زوجة أبي،
the Empress of Beizhao.
إمبراطورة بيتشاو.
Such behavior
هذا السلوك
is improper!
هذا غير لائق!
Xiao...
شياو...
Qing'er, you're here.
تشينغ إير، أنت هنا.
As you hadn't returned,
بما أنك لم تعد،
I came looking for you.
جئت أبحث عنك.
What did you say to Her Majesty?
ماذا قلت لجلالة الملكة؟
Why is she crying so much?
لماذا تبكي كثيراً؟
She chose to cry.
اختارت أن تبكي.
Wenjing, she is the Empress.
وينجينغ، هي الإمبراطورة.
You should show her some respect.
يجب أن تُظهر لها بعض الاحترام.
Alright, I'll listen to you.
حسناً، سأستمع إليك.
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك،
we shall take our leave now.
سنغادر الآن.
Stop!
قف!
Let him go!
أطلق سراحه!
Don't you bully her!
لا تتنمر عليها!
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك،
are you alright?
هل أنت بخير؟
She is your Qing'er.
إنها تشينغ إير خاصتك.
Then who am I?
إذن من أنا؟
You are the Empress of Beizhao.
أنتِ إمبراطورة بيتشاو.
Qing'er, let's go.
تشينغ إير، هيا بنا.
Xiao Wenjing,
شياو ون جينغ
do you prefer kebabs or spicy hot pot?
هل تفضل الكباب أم طبق الهوت بوت الحار؟
How about a beach barbecue?
ما رأيك بحفلة شواء على الشاطئ؟
Yes! I haven't been to the beach for long.
نعم! لم أذهب إلى الشاطئ منذ فترة طويلة.
Since I'm the heroine,
بما أنني البطلة،
you must be the hero.
يجب أن تكون أنت البطل.
In our female-centric stories,
في قصصنا التي تتمحور حول النساء،
whoever the heroine chooses is the hero.
من تختاره البطلة هو البطل.
No arguments.
لا جدال في ذلك.
Nice to meet you.
سعيد بلقائك.
Nice to meet you too.
سُعدت برؤيتك.
♪Unwilling to become a passerby♪
♪غير راغب في أن يصبح عابر سبيل♪
So,
لذا،
do you really disappear?
هل تختفي حقاً؟
♪It's the cloud that favors, embracing the rivers♪
♪إنها السحابة التي تُفضّل، وتحتضن الأنهار♪
♪I am the lotus in the pond, suffering day and night♪
أنا زهرة اللوتس في البركة، أعاني ليلاً ونهاراً.
♪I only pray for snowfall♪
♪أدعو فقط أن تتساقط الثلوج♪
(What exactly happened?)
(ما الذي حدث بالضبط؟)
Greetings, Your Majesty.
تحية طيبة يا صاحب الجلالة.
News from the Cold Palace
أخبار من القصر البارد
is that Empress Dowager is about to give birth.
إن الإمبراطورة الأرملة على وشك الولادة.
Empress Dowager Chen Wanyi?
الإمبراطورة الأرملة تشين وان يي؟
She's still alive?
هل ما زالت على قيد الحياة؟
Yes.
نعم.
She's about to give birth.
إنها على وشك الولادة.
What happened?
ماذا حدث؟
(Even if she was pregnant,)
(حتى لو كانت حاملاً،)
(it's only been three months.)
(لم يمضِ سوى ثلاثة أشهر.)
(How can she give birth?)
(كيف يمكنها أن تلد؟)
(But she is alive,)
(لكنها على قيد الحياة،)
(perhaps from her,)
(ربما منها،)
(I can find a different answer.)
(يمكنني إيجاد إجابة مختلفة.)
I don't know either.
لا أعرف أيضاً.
But Your Majesty instructed
لكن جلالتكم أمرت
to invite you there
لدعوتك إلى هناك
on the day she gives birth,
في يوم ولادتها،
saying you want to see
قولك إنك تريد أن ترى
what kind of monster
أي نوع من الوحوش
she will give birth to.
ستلد.
(Did I say something so wicked?)
(هل قلت شيئاً بهذه القسوة؟)
(Never mind, I'll go check it out.)
(لا بأس، سأذهب لأتحقق من الأمر.)
Take me there.
خذني إلى هناك.
Yes.
نعم.
Get out!
اخرج!
Get out of here!
اخرج من هنا!
♪Spring comes late after the snow♪
♪يأتي الربيع متأخراً بعد الثلج♪
♪Having endured sorrow and joy♪
♪بعد أن تحملنا الحزن والفرح♪
♪Wandering the streets, the story unfinished♪
♪أتجول في الشوارع، والقصة لم تكتمل♪
♪Turning around, I lost you♪
♪استدرت، ففقدتك♪
♪Separated by the dust of the past♪
♪يفصل بينهما غبار الماضي♪
♪Our reunion veiled by moonlight♪
♪لقاءنا محجوب بضوء القمر♪
♪Grant me indifference or tenderness♪
♪امنحني اللامبالاة أو الحنان♪
♪Crowds push past, brushing shoulders♪
♪تتدافع الحشود، وتتلامس الأكتاف♪
♪Love grows wild within the soul♪
♪ينمو الحبّ بعنفٍ في أعماق الروح♪
♪Longing weaves into a net♪
♪الشوق ينسج في شبكة♪
♪Dare not speak, dare not gaze♪
♪لا تجرؤ على الكلام، لا تجرؤ على النظر♪
♪Yet I crave your glance♪
♪لكنني أتوق إلى نظرتك♪
♪Time, leaving many pasts behind♪
♪الزمن، يترك وراءه الكثير من الماضي♪
♪Desolation follows splendor♪
♪يتبع الخراب البهاء♪
♪Only after seeing enough worldly absurdity♪
♪فقط بعد رؤية ما يكفي من سخافات الدنيا♪
♪Will I kiss your face♪
♪هل سأقبل وجهك؟♪
♪Never forgotten, hope you've been well♪
لن ننساك أبدًا، أتمنى أن تكون بخير
♪Borrowing the first ray of spring light♪
♪استعارة أول شعاع من ضوء الربيع♪
♪Can it bring about for us?♪
♪هل يمكن أن يحقق لنا ذلك؟♪
♪One look back, lasting till the end of time♪
♪نظرة واحدة إلى الوراء، تدوم إلى نهاية الزمان♪
♪Love grows wild within the soul♪
♪ينمو الحبّ بعنفٍ في أعماق الروح♪
♪Longing weaves into a net♪
♪الشوق ينسج في شبكة♪
♪Dare not speak, dare not gaze♪
♪لا تجرؤ على الكلام، لا تجرؤ على النظر♪
♪Yet I crave your glance♪
♪لكنني أتوق إلى نظرتك♪
♪Time, leaving many pasts behind♪
♪الزمن، يترك وراءه الكثير من الماضي♪
♪Desolation follows splendor♪
♪يتبع الخراب البهاء♪
♪Only after seeing enough worldly absurdity♪
♪فقط بعد رؤية ما يكفي من سخافات الدنيا♪
♪Will I kiss your face♪
♪هل سأقبل وجهك؟♪